

Ho Chi Minh Citv. Vietnam

□ (+84)342724240 | ☑ ero.nguyen1905@gmail.com | ♠ nero1342.site | ☑ nero1342 | ் ☐ nero1342 | ➢ Google Scholar

Summary.

Passionate Computer Science graduate with a focus on Computer Vision, Machine Learning, and Algorithms. I bring 3 years of experience in developing algorithms for image and video understanding, as well as 6 years of competitive programming. Seeking a challenging role in the field of computer vision and machine learning where I can utilize my skills and knowledge to contribute to cutting-edge projects and advance my career.

Education

University of Science, VNU-HCM

Ho Chi Minh City, Vietnam

Aug. 2018 - Dec. 2022

B.S. IN COMPUTER SCIENCE | Advanced Program in Computer Science

- GPA: 3.94 / 4.00
- Graduated within the top 5/120 of my cohort
- Received full-year scholarship for freshman of the Advanced Program in Computer Science (2018)
- Received half-year scholarship for excellent student of the Advanced Program in Computer Science (2020, 2021)
- · Relevant courses: Artificial Intelligence, Computer Vision, Linear Algebra, Algorithm and Complexity, Number Theory

Skills

- Language: Vietnamese (Native), English (Professional)
- Programming: Python, C/C++
- Developer Tools: Git/Github, Docker, Jupyter Notebook
- Frameworks/Libraries: PyTorch, Keras, OpenCV, NumPy, SciPy, Matplotlib, Pandas
- Soft skills: Problem Solving, Communication, Teamwork, Critical Thinking

Work Experience

Software Engineering Laboratory, University of Science, VNU-HCM

Ho Chi Minh City, Vietnam

RESEARCH ASSISTANT

Sep. 2019 - Sep. 2022

May. 2021 - Feb. 2022

- Proposed, discussed and implemented methods in several projects in computer vision and artificial intelligence (Intelligence Traffic System, Video Object Segmentation, Referring Expression Segmentation, Medical Image Diagnosis and Visual Life-logging).
- Collected, and presented papers, findings for weekly seminars.
- Advisor: Assoc. Prof. Minh-Triet Tran

VinAl Research

Ho Chi Minh City, Vietnam

RESEARCH INTERN

- Researched on the Computer Vision task of Semi-supervised Video Object Segmentation.
 Analysed and reproduced state-of-the-art methods on this topic.
- Proposed and implemented an upgraded model from previous SOTA approaches to speed up 25% when inference.
- Advisors: Assoc. Prof. Minh-Hoai Nguyen & Assoc. Prof. Minh-Triet Tran

Projects

Smart Interactive Retrieval of Visual Data via Semantic Understanding

Ho Chi Minh City, Vietnam

THESIS PROJECT

Feb. 2022 - Aug. 2022

- · Developed an interactive retrieval system with multiple effective filter algorithms to search and retrieve relevant images fast and accurately.
- Deployed a referring expression segmentation module to enhance the explainability of the retrieval system.
- Integrated and took advantages from OpenAI's CLIP to align text prompts and images.
- Converted, stored and indexed millions of images as vector embeddings using Milvus.
- Achievement: Got 10/10 in thesis defense, First Prize in Student Scientific Research Award (EURÉKA).
- Technologies: PyTorch, OpenCV, Django, ReactJS, Milvus, Elasticsearch

Referring Expression Segmentation

Ho Chi Minh City, Vietnam

PERSONAL PROJECT

April. 2022 - Jul. 2022

- · Led a team of two to build an approach for the problem Referring Image Segmentation and Referring Video Object Segmentation.
- · Designed and implemented a new transformer-based method to gather multimodal information efficiently.
- Achievement: State-of-the-art on Referring Image Segmentation datasets, ranked 6th on YouTube-VOS 2021.
- · Technologies: PyTorch, OpenCV, Flask

Vietnamese Scene Text Recognition

Ho Chi Minh City, Vietnam

PERSONAL PROJECT

Oct. 2021 - Dec. 2021

- Led a team of four to build a solution for the detection and recognition of Vietnamese words in Scene Text images.
- Proposed a heuristic algorithm to fix and eliminate wrong words, which boosts 3% in performance.
- Achievement: First Prize in the Ho Chi Minh city Al Challenge 2021.
- Frameworks/Technologies: PyTorch, OpenCV, Docker

FEBRUARY 3, 2023 E-RO NGUYEN · RÉSUMÉ

Honors & Awards
COMPETITIVE PROGRAMMING

2022	Fourth Place, The 2021 ICPC Asia Hanoi Regional Contest	Hanoi, Vietnam
2022	Champion, The 2021 ICPC National Vietnam Contest	Vietnam
2021	Top 62nd, Facebook Hacker Cup 2021	Online
2019	Bronze Medal, The 2019 ICPC Asia Danang Regional Contest	Da Nang, Vietnam
2019	Fourth Prize, Samsung Collegiate Programming Cup 2019 Final Round	Seoul, Korea
2018	Participant, Asia-Pacific Informatics Olympiad	Russia

ARTIFICIAL INTELLIGENCE

2022	First Prize, Student Scientific Research Award(EURÉKA)	HCMC, Vietnam
2022	Sixth Place, The 4th Large-scale Video Object Segmentation Challenge	New Orleans, U.S.A
2021	First Prize, Ho Chi Minh City Al-Challenge 2021	HCMC, Vietnam
2020	Fourth & Sixth Place, The 2020 DAVIS Challenge on Video Object Segmentation	Online

Publications.

Visual-Language Transformer for Referring Video Object Segmentation

E-RO NGUYEN, NHAT HOANG-XUAN, MINH-TRIET TRAN

May 2022

Flexible Interactive Retrieval SysTem 3.0 for Visual Lifelog Exploration

IMCR'22

CVPRW'22

June 2022

MediaEval'21

CVPRW'20

Jun. 2020

NHAT HOANG-XUAN, HOANG-PHUC TRANG-TRUNG, E-RO NGUYEN, THANH-CONG LE, MINH-TRIET TRAN

Attention-based Hierarchical Fusion Network for Predicting Media Memorability

E-RO NGUYEN, HAI-DANG HUYNH-LAM, HAI-DANG NGUYEN, MINH-TRIET TRAN

Dec. 2021

PointRend with Attention Fusion Refinement for Polyps Segmentation

E-Ro Nguyen, Hai-Dang Nguyen, Minh-Triet Tran

Dec. 2021

Video Object Segmentation with Memory Augmentation and Multi-Pass Approach

The-Anh Vu-Le, Hong-Hanh, E-Ro Nguyen, Minh-Triet Tran

Extracurricular Activity

Free ContestHCMC, VietnamPROBLEM SETTERAug. 2017 - Mar. 2021

Creating the algorithmic problems in free algorithmic contest for the community in Vietnam.

Student Activities Board HCMC, Vietnam

FOUNDING MEMBER Aug. 2017 – Mar. 2021

• Hosts student activities in university with several topics: academic, entertainment, volunteer, and sport.

References

1. Minh-Triet Tran tmtriet@fit.hcmus.edu.vn

VICE PRESIDENT, HEAD OF SOFTWARE ENGINEERING LAB, DEPUTY HEAD OF ARTIFICIAL INTELLIGENCE LAB – UNIVERSITY OF SCIENCE, VNU-HCM, VIETNAM

2. Minh-Hoai Nguyen minhhoai@cs.stonybrook.edu

PRINCIPAL RESEARCH SCIENTIST & HEAD OF SMART EDGE - VINAI RESEARCH; DEPARTMENT OF COMPUTER SCIENCE - STONY BROOK UNIVERSITY, USA

FEBRUARY 3, 2023 E-RO NGUYEN · RÉSUMÉ